Guide to the Robert College records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XIII: Historical Writings
  - Newspaper articles on Robert College, ca. 1917, 1928 (Box 51, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Newspaper articles on Lausanne Treaty, 1927 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper articles on Robert College and Turkey, 1920s-1930s (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper articles on Robert College, 1920s (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper articles on Gates and Robert College, 1920s, 1940, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper articles on Robert College, 1930s-1950s (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Clippings on Atatürk's death and Inönü's election, 1938 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper articles on Robert College, 1960s (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Message of General Cemal Gürsel, Head of State of the Turkish Republic on the occasion of the Turkish American Celebration, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Remarks by Adlai E. Stevenson at Robert College Board of Trustees Banquet, April 18; also, message sent by John Kennedy, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - "Robert College in its Centennial Year," address given by President Patrick Murphy Malin, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - "Robert College of Istanbul, Centennial Year, 19621963," Program of Centennial Dinner held October 17, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 20)
  - Excerpts from an address given by Averrell Harriman, Assistant Secretary of State for Far Eastern Affairs, at the Centennial Dinner in New York, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Program of Centennial celebration held at Robert College, May 18, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Centennial booklets, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - Biographical Material
    - Dr. C.Gates: An Appreciation, published by the Robert College Herald Board of 1931-32 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Biographical sketch of Gates, ca. 1940s (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Biographical material on Gates, 1970s (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Herbert Lane's correspondence with Gates family, 1960s-1970s (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Biographical information on Dodge family and on E.D.H. Clarke, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Dodge family sketch and interview with Bayard Dodge, 1950s (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Biographical sketch of Hamlin published by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, 1907 (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Biographical information on Hamlin with correspondence by researchers, 1985 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Material on Hamlin, 1960s (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Profile of George Washburn by Lane, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Biographical material on Washburn collected by Lane, 1970s (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence re Arthur Washburn (grandson of George Washburn), 1971 (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - C.R. Robert: family history with cover letter, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - Biographical material on Robert, 1970s (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - Historical/General: (Box 51)
    - Material relating to legal suit contesting Robert's will, 1881-1883 (Box 52, Folder 1 to 2)
    - "The Founders of Robert College," by Lane, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - "Panorama of Constantinople, 1806," by Murhard, 1807 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - "A Private Journal," written by Ward M. Beckwith, 1881 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - "Historical Sketch of the Missions of the American Board in Turkey" and "Sunday School Missionary Concert Exercise", 1889, 1895 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - "The Duty of the United States to American Citizens in Turkey," by Everett Wheeler, 1896 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - "American Territory in Turkey" an address by Ralph Prime, 1908 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - "Sunshine in Turkey," by Howard S. Bliss, 1909 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "Exit the Turk," by H.G. Dwight, [undated] (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - "Lausanne Treaty -Relation with Robert College", ca. 1919 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - "The American Club of Constantinople, 1921-1922", 1922 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence Gates/Charles Robert, grandson of Robert, 1928 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Typescripts on topics pertaining to Turkish history, 1930s (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Keith Greenwood; notes for dissertation and outline of chapters, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Greenwood; notes from microfilm of Robert-Hamlin correspondence (1868-1871), 1960s (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Greenwood; general notes on the early years at Robert College, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Greenwood; typed excerpts from correspondence written by Hamlin, Robert, Washburn, George A. Perkins, 1862-1870 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Greenwood; typescript entitled "Washburn's Personal Recollections", 1960s (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Greenwood; typed notes on Washburn's correspondence for 1873-1874, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Greenwood; typed notes re Hamlin's thoughts, excerpts of Hamlin- Robert-Washburn letters, extract of Robert's autobiography, and Hamlin's memorandum to his children, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Greenwood: typed notes include a short biography of Robert possibly written by Harold Scott, a brief early history of the college, excerpt from a letter written by William Dwight to Washburn, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Greenwood: typed excerpts from Robert's correspondence, 1960s (Box 52, Folder 23 to 24)
    - Correspondence from the Byzantine Institute, 1947-1950 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - The Turkish Straits and the Great Powers, by Cyril Black, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Reprints of articles written by Walter Wright, "Truths about Turkey," and "Our Near Eastern Policy in the Making", 1948 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - "An Experiment in Bilingual, Bicultural Education" by David Garwood, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - "American Alma Maters in the Near East," by Maynard Owen Williams, reprint from the National Geographic Magazine, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Commemorative booklet on David A. Scott (son of Mr. and Mrs. Harold L. Scott), 1924-1944, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - "American Doctors in the Crimean War, 1857-1855," by Albert Parry. Also contains correspondence Parry/Scott, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - "The World at the Time of the Opening of Robert College," by Herbert Lane, 1961 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Translation of a document issued to Hamlin with reference to permission to establish a school, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - "Some 16th and 17th century visitors to Constantinople" (author unknown), [undated] (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - John Dewey: his works on Turkey, bibliography with Xerox reprints, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Film scripts, 1970s (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Manuscripts and typescripts (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous notes on Robert College history, [undated] (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - "A History of Robert College 1858-1878" Chapter 1, "Loomings," ms. Notes, [undated] (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - History of Campus at Bebek with abstracts of correspondence prepared by W.Clarke, 1868 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Summary of facts relating to purchase of land at Rumeli Hisar (Bebek Campus) prepared by Clarke, 1868 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - "Robert College," synopsis of college history written by George Washburn, [undated] (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Description of the founding of Robert College apparently written by George Washburn, [undated ca. 1903] (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - "Robert College," by Gates, 1903 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "Return to the Straits," by Floyd Black (a chapter from ms. entitled "A Brief Account of My Experience at Robert College"), 1919-1925 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - "Survey of Education in Turkey," by L.A. Scipio, 1926 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - "Robert College," a short history written by Gates, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Notes on history and status of Robert College and other educational institutions [Scott?], 1950s (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "Foreign Schools in Turkey, 1914-1926," by Scott, 1927 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Unfinished history of Robert College, by Scott, 1950s (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - "Robert College in Istanbul" by Jane N. Page (reprint from The Chapin School Alumnae Bulletin), 1960s (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - "Robert College -Its History," by Greenwood, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence relating to the early history of Robert College, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Article on athletics at Robert College by Kerry Wood, athletic director, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Outline for a Robert College history written by Hilary Sumner Boyd, with correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Paper on education in Turkey, written by Edward Webster, director of the Orta School, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Ms. entitled "A Legacy on the Bosphorus" (incomplete) written by Sylvia Kuran, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Ms. entitled "The Robert College Natural History Museum," by Esref Sakarya, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - "The Robert College Natural History Museum," Sakarya, 1982 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - "Memoirs," years at Robert College Boarding School (1938-1946) by Ali Neyzi, Part I, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - "Memoirs," by Neyzi, Part II (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - "Memoirs," by Neyzi, Part III (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - "Floyd Hensen Black, 1883-1983 A Remembrance by his Son," Cyril Edwin Black, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 26)
    - "Istanbul Amerikan Robert Lisesi: the Orphan Child of Robert College and American College for Girls" by Harry Dawe, 1986 (Box 54, Folder 27)
- Series XIV: Oversize and Miscellaneous Material
  - Christopher R. Robert; autobiography, [undated] (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Hamlin correspondence to Robert, [undated] (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper articles re Robert, [undated] (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten essay on Benjamin Franklin by Hamlin, [undated] (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - The Times, London, entire issue devoted to Turkey, 1938 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - A copy of the "Treaty of Peace with Turkey," signed Sèvres, August 10, 1920 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Records of the Engineering School, includes reports and curricula, 1916-1955 (Box 55, Folder 7 to 13)
  - Ford Foundation, proposals for projects at Robert College, 1950s (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of the President's Advisory Committee, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - 75th Anniversary booklets (6 copies), 1938 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Congratulations from U.S. colleges honoring 100th anniversary of Robert College (1963), 1963 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications on Turkey (Box 56, Folder 3 to 11)
  - "Copie de Lettres", April 1, 1863-November 21, 1864 (bound volume, mostly blank) (Box 57)
  - Extracts from the Correspondence of the President, Director and Treasurer of Robert College of Constantinople Essential to its History, February 7, 1868-December 31, 1872 (Box 57)
  - Extracts from the Correspondence of the President, Director and Treasurer of Robert College of Constantinople Essential to its History, Volume 3, January 1873-January 1875 (Box 57)
  - The Orient, 1914-1915 (Box 58)
  - The Karacan Case, 1943, (3 Folders) (Box 59)
  - Correspondence to Paul Monroe from U.S. Consulate regarding Edgar Fisher, 1933-1934 (Box 59)
  - Memos re. sensitive materials, 1961-1986 (Box 59)
  - Donkey incident, 1925 (Box 59)
  - Sensitive [material] marked, to discuss, 1970s (Box 59)
  - RC.NY Office. Commencements: telegrams/programs, 1971-1985 (Box 59)
  - Unsigned copy of a letter to Senator Lodge re. Armenians, 1923 (Box 59)
  - C.Gates "Problem of an Armenian Principality" 1919 (Box 59)
  - Memo to trustees submitted by Paul Monroe "on the Attitude of Government Officials and Turkish People Towards the American Colleges" 1934 (Box 59)
  - File 9 – Hold (Box 59)
  - Materials from Duncan Ballantine’s papers to review for sensitivity (Box 59)
  - Middle East Survey Commission Report, 1961, (2 Folders) (Box 59)
  - Robert College – Old and New (4 copies) (Box 60)
  - Development of the American College for Girls at Istanbul by Marjorie L. McKillop (M.A. theses), 1949, (2 Folders) (Box 60)
  - Kemmerer report on the economic situation in Turkey, 1934 (3 Folder) (Box 60)
  - Pocket dictionaries (5) and date books (5), 1926-1932 (Box 61)
  - RC Student Handbook 1972-1973 (2 copies) (Box 61)
- Series XV: Photographs
  - Students at Work Library; students Laboratory Classroom studying
  - Students, Informal Students, Extracurricular (includes clubs, social service) (Box 63)
  - Students, Groups (Box 64-65)
  - Students, (includes Groups commencement photographs) (Box 66)
  - Sports, Field Day (Box 67)
  - Sports Teams Action shots (Box 68)
  - Faculty, Groups (Box 69)
  - Faculty, Individuals (Box 70)
  - Bebek and Early Years (Box 71)
  - Administrators Founders (Hamlin, Washburn, Robert) and Presidents (Gates, Monroe) (Box 72)
  - Administrators: Presidents and Headmasters (Box 73)
  - Administrators: Vice-presidents, deans, officials on campus and in New York Office (Box 74)
  - l00th Anniversary celebration Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, 1963 (Box 75-76)
  - Visitors to Campus (Box 77)
  - Individuals (Box 78)
  - Groups (Box 79)
  - RC/ACG Alumni/ae (Box 80)
  - Theater, Music, Folklore (Box 81)
  - Students at Work Students Studying Laboratory Classroom Students, Informal (Box 82)
  - Sports Theater Commencement photographs I (Box 83)
  - Faculty and Administrators (Box 84)
  - Language Laboratory Natural History Collection (Box 85)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) General views (many with Bosphorus) (Box 86)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) General views Aerial views (Box 87)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) General views (Box 88)
  - Computer Center (Box 89)
  - RC Campus Buildings, Groups (pre-1971) (Box 90)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) Individual buildings (Hamlin, Theodorus, Anderson Halls) Washburn, Albert Long, Theodorus, Anderson Halls) (Box 91)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) Individual Buildings (Sloane Infirmary, Kennedy Lodge, Engineering Building, Library; interiors) (Box 92)
  - Robert College Campus (pre-197l) Individual buildings, misc. (The Old Study Hall, Henrietta Washburn.. .) Construction photographs (Box 93)
  - Robert College Campus (post-197l) General views, construction photographs, New buildings (Feyyaz Berker Hall, Nejat Eczacibasi Gym, Suna Kirac Theater) (Box 94)
  - Robert College Campus (post-197l) Tennis Courts; Etiler Gate (1990); Dorr Athletic Field renovation and dedication (Box 95)
  - RC: Alumni and Friends; The World of Robert College; Treasures from the Archives of RC:; Trustee/Alumni Reception; 125th Anniversary Celebration; Multivision Slide Presentation at the River Club, NY; "Love in the Turkish Arts" lecture by H.E. Talat Halman; RC Student Reunion; Round Table and Reception, NY’ "In Search of the Imperial City" lecture by Dr. Walter Denny; American-Turkish Friendship Council Reunion, Washington, DC. (Box 96)
  - RC (pre-1971)/ACG Miscellaneous photographs (Box 97)
  - RC (pre-1971)/ACG Miscellaneous photographs (Box 98)
  - Robert College (pre-1971)/ACG (Box 99)
  - Album titled "Souvenir of the Construction of new Gymnasium-Annex to Theodorus Hall" (Box 99)
  - Album of ACG photographs, 1937 (Box 99)
  - Album of Robert College and Istanbul (G. H. Huntington) (Box 99)
  - Robert College (pre-1971) 3 Albums (Robert College, ACG, Istanbul) (Box 100)
  - RC (post-1971) Miscellaneous photographs (Box 101)
  - Istanbul, General (Box 102)
  - Istanbul, General (Box 103)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 104)
  - Slides:
    - Robert College (post-197l) (Box 105)
    - Faculty, Administrators (Box 105)
    - Students at Work: Studying, Laboratory, Assembly (Box 105)
    - Students: Informal (Box 105)
    - Theater, Music, Folklore (Box 105)
    - Sports (Box 105)
    - Commencements (Box 105)
    - Campus/Buildings (Box 105)
    - Heritage Room; Child Study Center; Audio-Visual Center; Computer Center (Box 105)
    - Trustees/Alumni/Friends (Box 105)
  - Negatives (35mm) RC (post-1971) (Box 106)
  - Computer Center (Box 106)
  - Campus Buildings (Box 106)
- Series XVI: Minutes
  - RC Minutes, 1863-November 1905 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - RC Minutes April 1906-November 1928 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - RC Minutes May 1929-August 1938 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - RC Minutes September 1938-February 1949 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - RC Minutes May 1949-September 1956 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - RC Minutes November 1956-September 1958 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - RC Minutes September 1958-November 1959 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - RC Minutes November 1959-November 1960 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - RC Minutes December 1960-January 1962 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - RC Minutes February 1962-July 1963 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Resident Trustees Minutes, 1960-1971 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - RC Minutes September 1963-November 1965 (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - RC Board of Trustees, 1964 (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - RC Board of Trustees, 1965 (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - RC Minutes 1966 (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - RC Minutes April 1965-October 1966 (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - RC Minutes November 1966-November 1967 (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - RC Board of Trustees, 1967 (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - RC Minutes 1968 (Box 109, Folder 19)
  - RC Minutes November 1967-December 1968 (Box 110, Folder 20)
  - RC Minutes 1969 (Box 110, Folder 21)
  - RC Minutes January 1969-December 1969 (Box 110, Folder 22)
  - RC Minutes 1970 (Box 110, Folder 23)
  - RC Minutes January 1970-June 1970 (Box 110, Folder 24)
  - RC Minutes 1971 (Box 110, Folder 25)
  - RC Minutes January 1971-December 1971 (Box 110, Folder 26)
  - RC Minutes 1972 (Box 111, Folder 27)
  - RC Minutes January 1972-October 1973 (Box 111, Folder 28)
  - RC Minutes September 1973-March 1975 (Box 111, Folder 29)
  - RC Minutes May 1975-May 1976 (Box 111, Folder 30)
  - RC Minutes January 1977-August 1978 (Box 111, Folder 31)
  - RC Minutes September 1978-October 1979 (Box 111, Folder 32)
  - RC Minutes February 1980-October 1982 (Box 111, Folder 33)
  - RC Minutes November 1982-March 1984 (Box 112, Folder 34)
  - RC Minutes May 1984-July 1985 (Box 112, Folder 35)
  - RC Minutes September 1985-February 1987 (Box 112, Folder 36)
  - RC Minutes May 1987-February 1989 (Box 112, Folder 37)
  - RC Minutes May 1989-February 1991 (Box 112, Folder 38)
  - RC Minutes April 1991-November 1992 (Box 112, Folder 39)
  - RC Minutes January 1993-June 1994 (Box 113, Folder 40)
  - RC Minutes July 1994-October 1995 (Box 113, Folder 41)
  - RC Minutes January 1996-November 1996 (Box 113, Folder 42)
- Series XVII: Audio Visual
  - Subseries XVII.1: Films
    - "Robert College Old and New", early 1970s, (8mm) (Box 114)
    - "Robert College Old and New", early 1970s, (2 reels; (16mm) (Box 114)
  - Subseries XVII.2: Audio Tapes (reel to reel)
    - Dedication of George Walbridge Perkins Engineering and Science Building, May 18,1963, (1200 ft on 1 ½ mil plastic base) (Box 114)
    - RC Special questions and answer session of RC Faculties and Grinnell Morris concerning security clearance, March 19, 1965, (1800 ft. on 1 mil acetate) (Box 114)
- Series XVIII: Architectural Plans and Drawings
  - Various unidentified plans in a tube Box. (Box 115)
  - Various flat plans and drawings. (Mapcase 14-O-4)
  - Various flat plans and drawings. (Mapcase 14-O-5)
- Series XIX: Microfilms
  - Nine microfilm reels: Near East College Association, Inc, (#1A1863 March 1958 November, 1967 – Pg. 2) – R.C. Board of Trustees. Minutes, 1880-1905 (filmed by John Hopkins) – Unidentified reel framents numbered 5-8. (Box 116)
- Series I: Heritage Room/Rare Books (Istanbul)
  - Catalogue (Box 1)
  - Museum Catalogues (Box 1)
  - General Archives/Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Deposition of Archives-Princeton University (Box 1)
  - Archives (Rare Books) (Box 1)
  - Heritage Room-Tricia's Visit & Notes (20 April, 1992) (Box 1)
  - Heritage Room-General (Box 1)
  - Heritage Room-Rare Books, List of (Box 1)
  - Archives-General (Box 1)
  - Guide to the Archives-Copyright Certificate (Box 2)
  - Projects-125th Anniversary (Box 2)
  - Projects-Microfilming (Box 2)
  - Reports-re: NY Office (includes Heritage Room) (Box 2)
  - Reports-re: Lutzker (Box 2)
  - Research Requests-General (Box 2)
  - Research Requests-made by NY Office Archivist (Box 2)
  - Demakis, Louise (Box 2)
  - Engelbourg, Saul (Box 2)
  - Freely, John (Box 2)
  - Gocek, Fatima Muge, Prof. (Box 2)
  - Harper, Helen (Box 2)
  - Kuran, Sylvia (Istanbul) (Box 2)
  - Petkov, Petko, Dr. (Box 2)
  - Reed, Howard A., Prof. (Box 2)
  - Stevens, Marcia and Malcolm (Box 2)
  - White, Malcolm (Box 2)
- Series II: Heritage Room/Rare Books (Istanbul & R.C./N.Y. Offices)
  - Dwight Simpson: Presidential Search (1961-1965) (Box 3)
  - Dwight Simpson: Correspondence (1965) (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Dwight Simpson: Correspondence (1965) (1 of 2) (Box 3)
  - Dr. Simpson: Correspondence re: Exchange Program (1965) (Box 3)
  - Secretary to the President, Miss Gulsen A. Bengisu-Correspondence (1965-1966) (Box 3)
  - Simpson Proposed Plan of Reorganization (1965-1966) (Box 3)
  - Dwight Simpson: Power of Attorney/Resignation (1965-1967) (Box 3)
  - Sims, Catherine (Dean) (Box 3)
  - Dwight Simpson-Correspondence (1966) (1 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Dwight Simpson-Correspondence (1966) (2 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Dwight Simpson-Correspondence (1966) (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Dwight Simpson Correspondence re: Articles on Roberts College (1966) (Box 4)
  - Dwight Simpson-Correspondence, telegrams (1967) (Box 4)
  - Search Committee: Faculty Liaison (1967-1968) (Box 4)
  - Search Committee: Notes, Correspondence (Box 4)
  - J. S. Everton-Press Releases on Appointment (1968) (Box 4)
  - Correspondence re: Everton Appointment (1968) (Box 4)
  - John Stuart Everton: Correspondence with Trustees/N.Y. Office, (1964 1967 1970) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont, John C. (1972-1976) (Box 4)
  - The Future of the Merged Lycee (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence (1971) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Principal of Robert Academy, Correspondence w. Catherine Rose (1971-1972) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont, Robert Academy Correspondence (1972) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Report on R.C. Community School (1972) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence (1972) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence: (1973) (1 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence: (1973) (2 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence: (1973) (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence: (1974) (1 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Chalfont: Correspondence: (1974) (2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Edwin Crocker-Frederick Utley Correspondence (1969-1970) (Box 7)
  - Helen White-Crocker: Correspondence with Utley re: Funds Operation, (1970-1975) (Box 7)
  - Meeting of the Executive Committee (12 November 1969) (Box 7)
  - Helen White: Correspondence with Utley (1971-1975) (Box 7)
  - Helen White (Controller)-application, correspondence (1971-1973) (Box 7)
  - Robert Hardy (1970) (Box 7)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1970) (Box 7)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1971-1973) (Box 7)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1974-1975) (Box 7)
  - R.C./Robert Hardy (1970) (Box 7)
  - Richard Reid, Principal, Robert Academy-Correspondence (1967-1970) (Box 7)
  - Brzozowski, Witold, Dean of Engineering School: Correspondence, (1963-1967) (Box 8)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1965) (Box 8)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1966) (Box 8)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1967) (Box 8)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1968) (Box 8)
  - Robert Hardy-General Correspondence (1969) (Box 8)
  - H.P. Hall: Report on the Colleges (1967) (Box 8)
  - Howard Hall, Acting President: Contract and Power of Attorney (1967) (Box 8)
  - Howard P. Hall, Correspondence (1968) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence between Hazen and Odgen (1960-1962) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence-Hazen to Ballantine, Hall (1960-1964) (Box 8)
  - Hazen Correspondence -Jane Page and Grinnell Morris (1961-1966 1971) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Harold Hazen to Patrick Malin (1962-1963) (Box 8)
  - Notes and Correspondence (1962-1966) (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (1965-1968) (Box 8)
  - Howard Hall: Correspondence (1964-1965) (Box 8)
  - VP Howard Hall: Correspondence (1965-1967) (Box 8)
  - Howard P. Hall: Correspondence (1967) (Box 8)